In this lesson, we'll be analyzing two datasets.
في هذا الدرس، سوف نحلل مجموعتي بيانات،
One, on red wine samples and the other on white wine samples from the north of Portugal.
إحداها حول عينات النبيذ الأحمر والأخرى حول عينات النبيذ الأبيض من شمال البرتغال.
Each wine sample comes with a quality rating from one to ten,
تأتي كل عينة للنبيذ مع تصنيف للجودة من 1 إلى 10،
and results from several physical chemical tests.
ونتائج من اختبارات كيميائية وفيزيائية عديدة.
That may sound like a big word,
قد يبدو هذا أمرًا ثقيلًا،
but it just means we'll be analyzing properties like alcohol content,
لكنه لا يعني سوى أننا سنحلل الخصائص مثل محتوى الكحول
acidity level, and residual sugar.
ومستوى الحموضة والسكر المترسب.
Here are the two data sets in a Jupyter notebook.
إليكم مجموعتي بيانات في دفتر الملاحظات Jupyter،
One at the red wine samples, and one of the white.
إحداها عند عينات النبيذ الأحمر والأخرى عند عينات النبيذ الأبيض.
Not including the index column,
باستثناء عمود الفهرس،
there are 11 columns describing their chemical properties,
هناك 11 عمودًا تصف الخصائص الكيميائية لهذه العينات
and a column for the quality ratings.
وعمود لتصنيفات الجودة.
If you are the owner of a vineyard or a wine store and you're given
إذا كان أحدكم مالكًا لحقل عنب أو متجر لبيع النبيذ، وتم تقديم
this data on almost 5,000 wine samples, how might you use it?
هذه البيانات له حول 5.000 عينة للنبيذ تقريبًا، كيف يمكنه استخدامها؟